<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>JobTech Development – </title>
    <link>/en/news/</link>
    <description>Recent content on JobTech Development</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    
	  <atom:link href="/en/news/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
      
        
      
    
    
    <item>
      <title>News: Get started with JobTech Development APIs</title>
      <link>/en/news/news_head/210316/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/en/news/news_head/210316/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        
        <![CDATA[<img src="/en/news/news_head/210316/featured_huea7838d5243b29c93f010c56ccf8b795_102938_640x0_resize_q75_catmullrom.jpg" width="640" height="466"/>]]>
        
        &lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;letterbox.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;identifierade ord&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;During the spring, JobTech Development will arrange open webinars for anyone who wants help getting started with our APIs. The first opportunity is Friday, March 26.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To make it even easier to use our APIs, we will organize four webinars in the spring where we provide a technical introduction and the opportunity to ask questions directly to our developers. The webinars are primarily aimed at new and existing users, but are open to anyone who wants to know more about how our APIs can be used for the development of digital services for the labor market.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At the webinars, our development team, represented by &lt;strong&gt;Johan Brymér Dahlhielm&lt;/strong&gt; and &lt;strong&gt;Henrik Suzuki&lt;/strong&gt;, will provide information and practical guidance for APIs such as &amp;ldquo;JobSearch&amp;rdquo;, &amp;ldquo;JobStream&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;JobTech Taxonomy&amp;rdquo;. This is followed by an open conversation with the opportunity to ask questions, give feedback and present ideas and wishes for new technical solutions from JobTech Development.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;“We look forward to helping and inspiring new users through this spring&amp;rsquo;s webinars. Through more dialogue and feedback, we also get a greater opportunity to improve our products and become more accurate when we develop new technical solutions for the labor market&amp;rdquo;&lt;/em&gt;, says &lt;strong&gt;Henrik Suzuki&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All webinars will be held according to the &amp;ldquo;open space&amp;rdquo; model, which means that the agenda and topics of conversation are largely governed by the participants&amp;rsquo; specific interests and needs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Date and registration:
&lt;style&gt;
    .main {
        width: 80%;

        background-color: #efefef;
        padding-top: 30px;
        padding-left: 30px;
        padding-bottom: 30px;
        border: 2px solid black;
        border-radius: 8px;
    }
    label {
    font-family: IBM plex sans;
    margin-bottom: 0px;
    
    }
    input{
    font-family: IBM plex sans ;
    }

    button {
        margin-top: 20px;
        border-radius: 3px;
    }

    
    input[type=text]{
        margin-bottom: 10px;

    }
    

    @media 
only screen and (max-width: 760px),
(min-device-width: 768px) and (max-device-width: 1024px)  {
    #form {
        width: 100%;
    }
   
    
    }
    .modal-body{
        height: 300px;

        overflow: auto;
       
    }
    .modal-content{
        white-space: pre-line;
    }
    


&lt;/style&gt;

&lt;div id=&#34;form&#34; class=&#34;main&#34;&gt;
    &lt;form action=&#34;/api/form&#34; id=&#34;idForm&#34;&gt;
        &lt;h6&gt;I sign up for...&lt;/p&gt;
   
        &lt;fieldset &gt;  
                   &lt;p class=&#34;text-danger&#34; id=&#34;message&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
               
                
                &lt;input type=&#34;checkbox&#34; id=&#34;21042310&#34; name=&#34;options[]&#34; value=&#34;23 april kl 10:00 - 10:30 Introduktion + Kom igång-tips (för användare)&#34;&gt;
                &lt;label for=&#34;21042310&#34;&gt;23 April kl 10:00 - 10:30 Introduction &amp;#43; Getting started (user)&lt;/label&gt;&lt;br&gt;                
                
                &lt;input type=&#34;checkbox&#34; id=&#34;2104231030&#34; name=&#34;options[]&#34; value=&#34;23 april kl 10:30 – 11:30 Frågor, feedback och diskussion (öppet för alla)&#34; &gt;
                &lt;label for=&#34;2104231030&#34;&gt;23April kl 10:30 – 11:30 Questions, feedback and discussion (open to everyone)&lt;/label&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;

                &lt;input type=&#34;checkbox&#34; id=&#34;21052810&#34; name=&#34;options[]&#34;value=&#34;28 maj kl 10:00 - 10:30 Introduktion + Kom igång-tips (för användare)&#34; &gt;
                &lt;label for=&#34;21052810&#34;&gt;28 May kl 10:00 - 10:30 Introduction &amp;#43; Getting started (user)&lt;/label&gt;&lt;br&gt;                
                
                &lt;input type=&#34;checkbox&#34; id=&#34;2105281030&#34; name=&#34;options[]&#34;value=&#34;28 maj kl 10:30 – 11:30 Frågor, feedback och diskussion (öppet för alla)&#34; &gt;
                &lt;label for=&#34;2105281030&#34;&gt;28 May kl 10:30 – 11:30 Questions, feedback and discussion (open to everyone))&lt;/label&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;

                &lt;input type=&#34;checkbox&#34; id=&#34;210061810&#34; name=&#34;options[]&#34;value=&#34;18 juni kl 10:00 - 10:30 Introduktion + Kom igång-tips (för användare)&#34; &gt;
                &lt;label for=&#34;31061810&#34;&gt;18 June kl 10:00 - 10:30 Introduction &amp;#43; Getting started (user)&lt;/label&gt;&lt;br&gt;                
                
                &lt;input type=&#34;checkbox&#34; id=&#34;2106181030&#34; name=&#34;options[]&#34;value=&#34;18 juni kl 10:30 – 11:30 Frågor, feedback och diskussion (öppet för alla)&#34;  &gt;
                &lt;label for=&#34;2106181030&#34;&gt;18 June kl 10:30 – 11:30 Questions, feedback and discussion (open to everyone) &lt;/label&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;                
                              
        &lt;/fieldset&gt; 
        
        &lt;fieldset&gt;
               
                &lt;label for=&#34;namn&#34;&gt;Name:&lt;/label&gt;&lt;br&gt;       
                &lt;input type=&#34;text&#34; name=&#34;namn&#34; id=&#34;namn&#34; pattern=&#34;^[a-zA-ZåäöÅÄÖ -]+$&#34; placeholder=&#39;Name (Required)&#39; autofocus  required oninvalid=&#34;this.setCustomValidity(&amp;#34;Please enter your name&amp;#34;)&#34; oninput=&#34;setCustomValidity(&#39;&#39;)&#34;&gt;&lt;br&gt;
                
                &lt;label for=&#34;email&#34;&gt;E-mail:&lt;/label&gt;&lt;br&gt;
                &lt;input type=&#34;email&#34; name=&#34;email&#34; id=&#34;email&#34; pattern=&#34;^[^\s@]+@[^\s@]+$&#34; placeholder=&#39;Email address (Required)&#39;   required oninvalid=&#34;this.setCustomValidity(&amp;#34;Please enter your email&amp;#34;)&#34; oninput=&#34;setCustomValidity(&#39;&#39;)&#34;&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt; 
                
                &lt;input type=&#34;checkbox&#34; id=&#34;consent&#34; name=&#34;consent&#34; value=&#34;1&#34; required oninvalid=&#34;this.setCustomValidity(&amp;#34;You need to approve the consent&amp;#34;)&#34;&gt;
                &lt;label for=&#34;consent&#34;&gt;I have read and I give my   &lt;a class=&#34;btn-link&#34; href=&#34;&#34; data-toggle=&#34;modal&#34; data-target=&#34;#licence&#34;&gt; consent &lt;/a&gt;to how my personal data will be handled. &lt;/label&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;                

                &lt;button type=&#34;submit&#34; name=&#34;skicka&#34; value=&#34;Submit&#34;&gt;Send&lt;/button&gt;
                &lt;button type=&#34;reset&#34; &gt;Clear&lt;/button&gt;
               
                
                &lt;input type=&#34;hidden&#34; id=&#34;language&#34; name=&#34;lang&#34;&gt;
        &lt;/fieldset&gt;   
    &lt;/form&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div class=&#34;modal fade&#34; id=&#34;licence&#34; tabindex=&#34;-1&#34; role=&#34;dialog&#34; aria-labelledby=&#34;licenceLable&#34; aria-hidden=&#34;true&#34;&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#34;modal-dialog modal-lg&#34; role=&#34;document&#34;&gt;
        &lt;div class=&#34;modal-content&#34;&gt;
            &lt;div class=&#34;modal-header&#34;&gt;
                &lt;h5 class=&#34;modal-title&#34; id=&#34;licenceLable&#34;&gt;Consent personal data&lt;/h5&gt;
                &lt;button type=&#34;button&#34; class=&#34;close&#34; data-dismiss=&#34;modal&#34; aria-label=&#34;Close&#34;&gt;
                    &lt;span aria-hidden=&#34;true&#34;&gt;&amp;times;&lt;/span&gt;
                &lt;/button&gt;
            &lt;/div&gt;
            &lt;div class=&#34;modal-body&#34; id=&#34;modalLicence&#34; onscroll=&#34;console.log(this.scrollTop);if(this.scrollTop+this.offsetHeight&gt;=this.scrollHeight){$(&#39;#agree&#39;).removeAttr(&#39;disabled&#39;)}&#34;&gt;
                &lt;div class=&#34;format&#34;&gt;                    
                    &lt;h3&gt;Consent JobTech Development   &lt;/h3&gt;
                    &lt;p&gt; I hereby agree that Arbetsförmedlingen, JobTech Development may save and store my personal information. 
 
 Personal information in the form of name and e-mail addresses is collected. The purpose of storing information, is to be able to send invitations and receive registrations for events. 
 
 Personal information is not passed on to third parties. 
 I can revoke my consent at any time by contacting the Swedish Public Employment Service via &lt;a href=&#34;mailto:jobtechdevelopment@arbetsformedlingen.se&#34;&gt;Jobtech Development&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;br&gt;      &lt;/p&gt;              
                &lt;/div&gt;
            &lt;div class=&#34;modal-footer&#34;&gt;

                &lt;button onclick=&#34;document.getElementById(&#39;consent&#39;).removeAttribute(&#39;disabled&#39;); if (!document.getElementById(&#39;consent&#39;).checked){document.getElementById(&#39;consent&#39;).click()};document.getElementById(&#39;consent&#39;).setCustomValidity(&#39;&#39;)&#34; id=&#34;agree&#34; type=&#34;button&#34; class=&#34;btn btn-primary&#34; disabled data-dismiss=&#34;modal&#34;&gt;I approve&lt;/button&gt;
            &lt;/div&gt;
        &lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;script&gt;
    $(&#34;#idForm&#34;).submit(function(e) {
            e.preventDefault(); 
            var form = $(this);
            var url = form.attr(&#39;action&#39;);
            document.getElementById (&#34;language&#34;).value = document.documentElement.lang;
            if (isAtLeastOneChecked(&#34;options[]&#34;)){
                    $.ajax({
                               type: &#34;POST&#34;,
                               url: url,
                               data: form.serialize(), 
                               success: function(data)
                               {    
                                                          
                                  $(&#34;#form&#34;).html(data.textString)
                               }
                         });
            }else{
                $(&#34;#message&#34;).html(&#34;You need to choose at least one occation&#34;)
            }

        
            
        });
         function isAtLeastOneChecked(name) {
                        let checkboxes = Array.from(document.getElementsByName(name));
                        return checkboxes.some(e =&gt; e.checked); 
        }
&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>News: No one can solve this problem by themselves; that’s why we’re doing it together</title>
      <link>/en/news/news_head/2102162/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/en/news/news_head/2102162/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        
        <![CDATA[<img src="/en/news/news_head/2102162/featured_huc73ae0280b9b6516759b25b34a1cebd4_87401_640x0_resize_q75_catmullrom.jpg" width="640" height="688"/>]]>
        
        &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;A collaboration project initiated by JobTech Development and involving Sweden’s major advertisement and job-matching actors, is going to make it possible to create a fully comprehensive presentation of all the job advertisements on the market – and job-seekers won’t need to worry about missing out on job opportunities. The technical system is currently being tested as a pilot in Platsbanken.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;









&lt;div class=&#34;card float-right m-6 m-5 rounded p-2 td-post-card mb-4 mt-4&#34; style=&#34;max-width: 310px&#34;&gt;
	&lt;img class=&#34;card-img-top&#34; src=&#34;/en/news/news_head/2102162/featured_huc73ae0280b9b6516759b25b34a1cebd4_87401_300x430_fill_q75_catmullrom_smart1.jpg&#34; width=&#34;300&#34; height=&#34;430&#34;&gt;
	
	&lt;div class=&#34;card-body px-0 pt-2 pb-0&#34;&gt;
		&lt;p class=&#34;card-text&#34;&gt;
&lt;small class=&#34;text-muted&#34;&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Matilda Adelborg, Blocket Jobb&lt;/small&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
	&lt;/div&gt;
	
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The collaboration project ”Ecosystem for advertisements” means that advertisements and job-matching actors will open up and share their job advertisement data in one joint digital ecosystem. The goal is partly to make it easier for job-seekers to navigate among job advertisements and find jobs, no matter what platform they are on, and partly to produce more documentation for Statistics Sweden’s labour market statistics.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;”We need to address the issue of digital restructuring which has led to, among other things, people currently having to navigate among many different advertisement platforms when looking for jobs, while not being sure whether they have access to all the available jobs. Neither Arbetsförmedlingen nor any other player can solve this problem by themselves, since no one has access to all job advertisements and that is why we are doing this together,”&lt;/em&gt; says &lt;strong&gt;Maria Dalhage&lt;/strong&gt;, project manager at  &lt;strong&gt;JobTech Development / Arbetsförmedlingen&lt;/strong&gt; which is providing the technical systems that are needed for the joint sharing and handling of advertisement data.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The actors who have entered the collaboration and thereby chosen to share their advertisement data are Blocket, CareerBuilder, Jobbdirekt, Monster, NetJobs, Offentliga Jobb, OnePartnerGroup and Studentjob. Together with the advertisements that are already presented in Platsbanken, this amounts to about 80 percent of the job advertisements on the market.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;””The pandemic has meant that we have more people looking for work at the same time as there are fewer job advertisements. Right now, it is more important than ever before to facilitate job-seeking, and as one of the largest commercial players in this field, it felt completely natural for us to be part of the collaboration”&lt;/em&gt;, says &lt;strong&gt;Matilda Adelborg&lt;/strong&gt;, press officer at Blocket Jobb.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;”At Monster, we are looking forward to this collaboration which is going to make it much easier for job-seekers to find a new and exciting job. This is completely in line with Monster’s goal which is to match up job-seekers and employers in the best possible way&lt;/em&gt;, says &lt;strong&gt;Per Wadell&lt;/strong&gt;, country manager på Monster.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The technical system – API ”JobTech Links” – will be tested initially as a pilot in Platsbanken.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;”With the pilot, we will study how the API works in practice and evaluate how the users perceive the interface. We will also follow up our partners’ experiences of the collaboration and ensure we have a sustainable model that is of benefit to all parties. We hope that more players will join us since our ultimate goal is to have one hundred percent of the advertisements”&lt;/em&gt;, says &lt;strong&gt;Maria Dalhage&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the long term, the system may become an open API which anyone can use to gain access to all advertisement links.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;em&gt;”Our aim is to create an open API but our main focus at the moment is to bring about successful cooperation and a sustainable model which we will be able to scale up”&lt;/em&gt;, concludes &lt;strong&gt;Maria Dalhage&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Do you or your company want to know more about “Ecosystem for advertisements” and how to join the collaboration?
&lt;a href=&#34;mailto:maria.dalhage@arbetsformedlingen.se&#34;&gt;Contact project manager Maria Dalhage.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>News: ”JobTech Development is a cutting-edge project that more people can learn from”</title>
      <link>/en/news/news_head/210118_intervju/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/en/news/news_head/210118_intervju/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        
        <![CDATA[<img src="/en/news/news_head/210118_intervju/featured_hu72887ccae3cae8df8e93d7f019869ac0_108711_640x0_resize_q75_catmullrom.jpg" width="640" height="855"/>]]>
        
        

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;…Johan Linåker, Lund University, who is a companion researcher to JobTech Development and has come halfway in his work to study how we, through collaboration and open data, build a digital ecosystem for the Swedish labor market&lt;/strong&gt;








&lt;div class=&#34;card float-right m-6 m-5 rounded p-2 td-post-card mb-4 mt-4&#34; style=&#34;max-width: 410px&#34;&gt;
	&lt;img class=&#34;card-img-top&#34; src=&#34;/en/news/news_head/210118_intervju/johanl_hudd885c4ea623352118e8e3d88f3da424_637175_400x360_fill_q75_catmullrom_smart1.jpg&#34; width=&#34;400&#34; height=&#34;360&#34;&gt;
	
	&lt;div class=&#34;card-body px-0 pt-2 pb-0&#34;&gt;
		&lt;p class=&#34;card-text&#34;&gt;

&lt;/p&gt;
	&lt;/div&gt;
	
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!-- There should be no margin above this first sentence.
&lt;!-- Blockquotes should be a lighter gray with a border along the left side in the secondary color.

&lt;!--There should be no margin below this final sentence.--&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;why-is-it-interesting-to-follow-jobtech-development&#34;&gt;Why is it interesting to follow JobTech Development?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;”It is very exciting to follow how you work with open data and open source software, and above all how you collaborate with actors within one and the same ecosystem around both the data and the software. With the research hat on, I can say that it is unique and forward-looking, and so far there is little reported and written in the field. The general debate in the public sector is focused on opening up and publishing your data, but there is a limited focus on collaboration and the connection to open source software. That is why JobTech Development and the ecosystem you are building is a cutting-edge project that many can learn from”&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;what-do-you-do-in-your-role-as-a-companion-researcher&#34;&gt;What do you do in your role as a companion researcher?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;”As a companion researcher, I have two roles. First is to help JobTech Development to build a sustainable ecosystem. I support, coach and provide input from research on how to collaborate on open data and open source software. Second, I follow how the ecosystem develops and compare with other examples in the outside world and give feedback to JobTech. I have, for example, compared with Trafiklab, which is Samtrafiken&amp;rsquo;s platform for open data connected to public transport in Sweden. I have also taken a closer look at open data ecosystems in Finland and the US. In addition, I work to spread knowledge about how authorities can use and collaborate on open data and open source software. One outcome is the newly formed Network for Open Source and Data (NOSAD.se) where we arrange workshops and gather materials that can help authorities in their work with these issues.”&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;you-have-come-halfway-into-your-work-what-have-you-come-up-with-so-far&#34;&gt;You have come halfway into your work. What have you come up with so far?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;”One insight is that authorities can collaborate on the data they open up in many different ways. JobTech Development is one example, Trafiklab another. What works best depends on the case. It has also been fun to see the strong synergy effect that exists between open source software and open data. Partly as a way to inspire how the data can be used and support developers implementing their solutions, partly to create transparency about how the data is used, and partly to enable the provision of the data. If a municipality is on a closed system, it can be so bad that they do not even have access to the data. ”&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;what-should-your-work-as-a-companion-researcher-lead-to&#34;&gt;What should your work as a companion researcher lead to?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;”I hope that it contributes to a stronger ecosystem, that more actors are added and that the data comes into use, and that this in turn leads to better matching between employers and jobseekers. I also hope that the work and research can help authorities, both in Sweden and internationally, to improve their work with open data and open source software. ”&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;how-can-those-who-are-interested-take-part-in-your-work&#34;&gt;How can those who are interested take part in your work?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;”A tip is to go to &lt;a href=&#34;https://Nosad.se.&#34;&gt;NOSAD&lt;/a&gt; There you can take part in research articles, open source policies, reports and training materials. I also share material via my Twitter and LinkedIn accounts (@johanlinaker).”&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In our &lt;a href=&#34;https://forum.jobtechdev.se/c/natverket-oppna-data-oppen-kallkod&#34;&gt;forum&lt;/a&gt; You can follow what happens in NOSAD and join discussions within the JobTech area.&lt;/p&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>News: ”We see that there is an unfulfilled demand for open data collaboration”</title>
      <link>/en/news/news_head/201001_intervju/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/en/news/news_head/201001_intervju/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        
        <![CDATA[<img src="/en/news/news_head/201001_intervju/featured_hu3f49752e89907e69d9bf1bbc2b4bd005_900205_640x0_resize_q75_catmullrom.jpg" width="640" height="758"/>]]>
        
        

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Five questions for&amp;hellip;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;…Jonas Södergren, Technical Manager at JobTech Development, and one of the initiators of “The Network for Open Data and Knowledge Sharing” which assembles participants from Swedish authorities for cross-border collaboration and practical sharing of open data.&lt;/strong&gt;








&lt;div class=&#34;card float-right m-6 m-5 rounded p-2 td-post-card mb-4 mt-4&#34; style=&#34;max-width: 310px&#34;&gt;
	&lt;img class=&#34;card-img-top&#34; src=&#34;/en/news/news_head/201001_intervju/jonas_hu3f49752e89907e69d9bf1bbc2b4bd005_900205_300x400_fill_q75_catmullrom_smart1.jpg&#34; width=&#34;300&#34; height=&#34;400&#34;&gt;
	
	&lt;div class=&#34;card-body px-0 pt-2 pb-0&#34;&gt;
		&lt;p class=&#34;card-text&#34;&gt;

&lt;/p&gt;
	&lt;/div&gt;
	
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!-- There should be no margin above this first sentence.
&lt;!-- Blockquotes should be a lighter gray with a border along the left side in the secondary color.

&lt;!--There should be no margin below this final sentence.--&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;why-is-this-network-needed&#34;&gt;Why is this network needed?&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;”Our contacts with other authorities show that there are many queries and challenges regarding to open data. These may have to do with anything from licences and legislation to solution of practical problems.  At the same time, the Government is increasingly pushing for Sweden to invest in open data and reuse of state resources. And so, we called around to find out what others are doing to reach out to users, what challenges they face, and how they measure investments and ensure benefits. When we realized that many people face exactly the same challenges,
the idea was born to create a network, where we help and inspire each other to move our work forward.”&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;who-has-joined-in&#34;&gt;Who has joined in?&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;”We, at JobTech Development and the Public Employment Service have created a planning group together with Samtrafiken, Digg, the Swedish Association of Local Authorities and Regions, the Internet Foundation, and the National Patent and Registration Office. Our workshops which, have been organised by us, have been attended by participants from over one hundred organisations, of which the majority were various authorities and other public actors.
A huge amount of interest has been shown, with workshops filled to the brim on both occasions, which makes us very happy!”&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;what-exactly-happens-at-the-network-meetings&#34;&gt;What exactly happens at the network meetings?&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;”The greater part of our first workshop was devoted to the discussion of licensing conditions which should apply to the authorities’ open data in Sweden. An official policy which the Patent and Registration Office is supposed to draw up is on its way, and we were all invited to participate in the discussion. Other than that, we discuss how to interact with each other, share our knowledge and inspire each other, for example, by providing practical examples.
We are also in the process of creating an open data portal for sharing data, where anyone who wants to can share their data with others in a concrete way.”&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;what-is-the-most-important-contribution-of-jobtech-development-the-public-employment-service-here&#34;&gt;What is the most important contribution of JobTech Development/the Public Employment Service here?&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;”We co-ordinate, harmonise and promote developmental changes, since we know that there is an unfulfilled need of collaboration. It is important that we start working in concrete terms with the here and now, and that we do not just sit and wait for a new law or something of that kind. We also contribute by showing other authorities what we are doing in the area of open data and open-source software – both as regards our successes and challenges facing us.”&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;what-do-you-hope-that-the-network-meetings-will-lead-to&#34;&gt;What do you hope that the network meetings will lead to?&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;” I hope that each respective authority will start sharing their resources and experiences to a larger degree than until now.
Many are used to sharing data if someone requires it, but we need to be more proactive.  Unfortunately, international surveys show that Sweden is lagging behind with regard do innovation based on open data, so there is certainly a big job to be done waiting for us. We have to make sure to get better survey results, and, ultimately, it has to do with creating a better life for those who live in Sweden”&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;WOULD YOU LIKE TO PARTICIPATE?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;”The Network for Open Data and Knowledge Sharing”&lt;/strong&gt; takes place on the first Tuesday of every month, and is open to all who wish to participate.”
&lt;a href=&#34;https://gitlab.com/open-data-knowledge-sharing/wiki/-/wikis/Digital-Workshopserie#kommande&#34;&gt;Please read more and register for the next meeting on 6 October.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Please note: the workshop can only accept a limited number of participants.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
